Long John Nebel Papers
Long John Nebel Papers
1962-1969
Nebel, Long John.
106.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American radio broadcaster (1911-1978). Correspondence; book manuscript; and audio tapes of interview and talk radio shows.
149386
Biographical History
"Long" John Nebel (1911- ) was an American radio broadcaster and talk show host. He began his career in radio broadcasting in 1954. In New York City he worked for WOR as host of a late night talk show before moving to WNBC in August, 1964. In 1972, he left WNBC for WMCA and remained there until his death in 1978. He conducted a variety of interview, talk, and telephone shows, including Addio, Long John Nebel All Night Show, Long John Nebel Early Hour, Long John Nebel Phone Show, Straight Line, Long John Nebel Versus, and Monitor.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Long John Nebel Papers contain correspondence, subject files, phonotapes, memorabilia and writings.
The majority of Correspondence is fan mail, with a few other incoming and outgoing items. Subject files cover topics such as communism, flying saucers, and religion. Published material contains advertisements, books, magazines, and newspapers. Writings consist of the manuscript, galley and page proofs of The Psychic World Around Us, written in collaboration with Sanford M. Teller in 1969. A small amount of Memorabilia completes the collection, and includes an index to the Addio programs.
The bulk of the collection (90 boxes) consists of phonotapes of the various talk, interview and telephone shows Nebel conducted over his career. With the exception of one 1962 recording, this group spans the years 1964-1969. The tapes measure 1/4"x2400' unless otherwise designated, and the tape speed appears in most cases to be 7-1/2" per second. Each entry gives the name of the show, the guests, and the topic of the show when known. When the airing date is different from the taping date both are given. Dates for repeated shows are also noted.
Each tape has a unique ID number, given in the inventory below, for example "#003-005." Please use the date and tape ID number when requesting items.
Nebel's programs dealt with a variety of topics, including religion, politics, medicine, and the theater. Many of the shows were concerned with psychic phenomena and the occult, with representative topics such as ESP, UFOs, hypnotism and spiritual healing. Name and topic indexes to the shows are available online or by contacting us; see Related Finding Aids below for more information.
Radio programs represented in the phonotapes, with inclusive dates of tapes in this collection, are:
Addio: Saturday evenings, 10:35 p.m. to 11:55 p.m. (January 8, 1967-January 27, 1968)
Long John Nebel All Night Show: Tuesday-Friday, 12 midnight to 5:00 a.m. Saturday and Sunday, 12 midnight to 6:00 a.m. (March 29, 1964-October 31, 1969)
Long John Nebel Early Hour: Monday-Friday, 8:05 p.m. to 9:00 p.m. (January 29, 1968- August 22-23, 1968)
Long John Phone Show: Monday-Friday, 7:45 p.m. to 8:00 p.m. (January 3, 1967-January 25, 1968)
Straight Line: Monday-Saturday, 5:00 a.m. to 6:00 a.m. (February 1, 1968-June 6, 1968)
Long John Nebel Versus: Monday-Friday, 8:05 p.m. to 9:00 p.m. (June 27, 1967- January 24, 1968)
Monitor: NBC Network weekend program (January 13, 1966-March 12, 1967)
Arrangement of the Collection
Tapes are physically arranged in chronological order regardless of show title. For ease of reference, the following inventory is ordered first by show, and then by date within each show.
Related Material
has the papers of many individuals in television and radio; please refer to for a complete listing.
Other Related Finding Aids
An alphabetical list of guests, with the date(s) and the show(s) on which they appeared, is available in PDF form online or by contacting the repository listed above.
A topical index, with the date(s) and the show(s), is also available in PDF form online or by contacting the repository listed above.
Subject and Genre Headings
Popular culture; Radio, television, film; Nebel, Long John.; Interviewing on radio.; Actors -- Interviews.; Authors -- Interviews.; Physicians -- Interviews.; Politicians -- Interviews.; Ministers -- Interviews.; Rabbis -- Interviews.; Radio broadcasters -- United States.; Radio broadcasting.; Radio programs.; Radio talk shows.; Audiotapes.; Correspondence.; Interviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Sound recordings.; Radio broadcasters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to the tapes requires advance notice for production of a listening copy. Listening copies are for onsite use only. Any person wishing to purchase a research copy will need to obtain permission from the copyright holder prior to placing their order.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Nebel, 1969.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - A-Z, unidentified, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Crank, unidentified
      - 1966, September-October, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1966, October-November, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - 1966 (Box 2)
      - 1966, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - 1966 (Box 4)
    - Fan mail
      - A-Z, unidentified, 17 folders (Box 5)
  - Outgoing
    - 1959, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence of others
    - O-W, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Kopper, Roberta, Sep 1966-Oct 1966 (Box 5)
- Subject files
  - Communism (Box 6)
  - Conservative Society of America (Box 6)
  - Dams and beautification (Box 6)
  - Divorce (Box 6)
  - Flying saucers (Box 6)
  - Phonograph record (Box 6)
  - Publishing (Box 6)
  - Receipts (Box 6)
  - Religion (Box 6)
  - Sheet music (Box 6)
  - Viet Nam (Box 6)
- Memorabilia
  - NBC News release and Look Magazine reprint, March 18, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Index to Addio programs, 1967-1968; descriptive listing of Nebel's radio shows (Box 7)
- Published material
  - Advertisements (Box 7)
  - Books
    - A-E (missing as of 7/09)
    - F-J (missing as of 7/09)
    - K-N (missing as of 7/09)
    - O-P, R-S (missing as of 7/09)
    - S-W (missing as of 7/09)
  - Magazines (missing as of 7/09)
  - Newspapers (missing as of 7/09)
  - Press releases (Box 7)
- Writings
  - The Psychic World Around Us, with Sanford M. Teller, 1969
    - Typescript, revised, pp. 1-254, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Galley (Box 7)
    - Page proofs, reproduction, fragments; 2 folders (Box 7)
- Tapes
  - Addio
    - "The Devil With James Bond" Mrs. Ann Boyd, Sanford Teller, January 8, 1967; nebel_0604; 1 reel (Oversize 31)
    - "Phones" Long John Nebel, January 14, 1967; nebel_0610; 1 reel (1/4"x1200') (Oversize 31)
    - Don MacLean, Richard Kollmar, January 21, 1967; nebel_0618; 1 reel (Oversize 31)
    - Selig Neubardt, January 28, 1967; nebel_0623; 1 reel (Oversize 32)
    - Fern Eckman, February 4, 1967; nebel_0633; 1 reel (Oversize 32)
    - Donald MacLean, -- Stanton, February 4, 1967; nebel_0634; 1 reel (Oversize 32)
    - John Rogge, Leonard L. Levinson, February 11, 1967; nebel_0645; 1 reel (Oversize 33)
    - Leon Sandow, February 18, 1967; nebel_0650; 1 reel (Oversize 33)
    - Don MacLean, Walter Gibson, February 18, 1967; nebel_0651; 1 reel (Oversize 33)
    - Dan Ross, February 25, 1967; nebel_0658; 1 reel (Oversize 33)
    - Christine Valmy, Dorman, February 25, 1967; nebel_0659; 1 reel (Oversize 33)
    - Mrs. Lex Leighton, March 2, 1967; nebel_0666; 1 reel (1/4"x1200') (Oversize 34)
    - Norman Jaspan, March 4, 1967; nebel_0669; 1 reel (1/4"x1200') (Oversize 34)
    - Buddha Joint, Fanny Lou Hamer, March 7, 1967; nebel_0673; 1 reel (Oversize 34)
    - Bill Mazer, March 18, 1967; nebel_0684; 1 reel (Oversize 35)
    - "Voluntary Sterilization" Boyd Lewis, Dr. Curtis Wood, Dr. Howard Miller, March 18, 1967; nebel_0685; 1 reel (Oversize 35)
    - "Women in Business," Cindy Adams, Lynn Caine, Roy Schatt, Will Ousler, March 25, 1967; nebel_0691-0693; 3 reel (Oversize 35)
    - (aired 1967 April 15) John Scully, March 27, 1967; nebel_0698; 1 reel (Oversize 35)
    - H. H. Scott, Edward Carmel, Donald MacLean, Sterling Yates, Dr. Hinsher, April 1, 1967; nebel_0699; 1 reel (Oversize 35)
    - Jean Shepherd, ? Mulholland, April 22, 1967; nebel_0716; 1 reel (Oversize 36)
    - James Moseley, Conrad Wadler, April 29, 1967; nebel_0720; 1 reel (Oversize 36)
    - Earle Doud, David Hoy, May 6, 1967; nebel_0723; 1 reel (Oversize 36)
    - Renee Taylor, George E. Freidman, May 13, 1967; nebel_0731; 1 reel (Oversize 37)
    - Lee Evans, Harold Weissberg, May 20, 1967; nebel_0738; 1 reel (Oversize 37)
    - (repeated 1969 July 20) Joseph Zimmatoré, December 2, 1967; nebel_0933; 1 reel (Oversize 47)
    - (repeated 1968 January 7) Arthur Tracy, Irving Settel, Max Lefcourt, January 4, 1968; nebel_0990; 1 reel (Oversize 50)
    - Daniel J. Debenedictis, Nathan Taylor, Dr. Jack Antelyes, January 13, 1968; nebel_1011; 1 reel (Oversize 50)
    - Lester Levy, Harry J. Trev, Eugene Sanger, Roy Cohn, January 20, 1968; nebel_1037; 1 reel (Oversize 52)
    - Murray Swartzman, Stephen Price, January 27, 1968; nebel_1045; 1 reel (Oversize 52)
    - "Dexion" (repeated 1968 April 25) Joseph X. Safina, January 27, 1968; nebel_1046; 1 reel (1/4"x1200') (Oversize 52)
  - Brad Crandall Show
    - Brad Crandall, September 20, 1965; nebel_0285; 1 reel (1/4"x1200'), 7" (Oversize 15)
  - LJN All Night Show
    - Albert Gallo, Ben Sternberg, Vincent Tracy, Mr. and Mrs. Bernard Krause, March 29, 1964; nebel_0004-0007; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 1)
    - "Every Night Josephine" Jacqueline Susann, Roy Schatt, Edith Aynes, Anna Marie Goetz, September 2, 1964; nebel_0008-0012; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 1)
    - Irving Caesar, Sanford Teller, Stewart Robb, September 9, 1964; nebel_0013-0017; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 1)
    - Brad Crandall, Samuel Vandervirt, Michael Kirsdansky, Bernard Korash, September 17, 1964; nebel_0018; 1 reel, 7" (Oversize 1)
    - Willie "The Lion" Smith, Danny Crystal, Miles Kreuger, Irving Caesar, September 18, 1964; nebel_0019-0023; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 1, 2)
    - (repeated 1965 January 5) June Havoc, Laurence Feldman, Shirley Herz, Danny Crystal, October 4, 1964; nebel_0024-0029; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 2)
    - "Taxes" (repeated 1964 December 29) Joseph Lefkowitz, Joseph Costa, Kenneth Knigin, Al Lottman, October 16, 1964; nebel_0030-0034; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 2)
    - "Strange World" Frank Edwards, Stewart Robb, Sanford Teller, Joe Lampl, John Jacobs, October 17, 1964; nebel_0035-0039; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 2, 3)
    - "Our Changing Constitution" (aired 1966 December 7) Charles Leedham, Joseph Kottler, Michael Girsbansky, Frederik Pohl, October 23, 1964; nebel_0040-0041; 2 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 3)
    - "Chiropractors" Mattis Yellin, Arthur Cohen, Dr. Howard Miller, Dr. Rowan, October 25, 1964; nebel_0042-0043; 2 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 3)
    - Dr. Ira Progoff, Stewart Robb, Frederik Pohl, October 30, 1964; nebel_0044-0048; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 3)
    - Conee Boswell, Frank Parker, Shirley Herz, Dee Anthony, November 8, 1964; nebel_0049-0054; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 3)
    - "The Medical Samaritans" Dr. Charles Goodrich, Sanford Teller, Dr. Howard Miller, Edith Aynes, November 13, 1964; nebel_0055-0059; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 3, 4)
    - Rev. Robert Schrock, Rabbi Theodore Ross, Ernest Partridge, Will Ousler, November 25, 1964; nebel_0060-0064; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 4)
    - "Cats" Milan Greer, Samuel Vandervirt, Edith Aynes, Jack Antelyes, December 2, 1964; nebel_0065-0069; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 4)
    - "The Protestant Establishment" Digby Baltzell, Frederik Pohl, Martin Berger, Kieren O'Doherty, December 3, 1964; nebel_0070-0074; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 4, 5)
    - Frederik Pohl, Lester Del Rey, Michael Girsdansky, December 5, 1964; nebel_0075-0079; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 5)
    - "The National Dividend" John Perry Jr., Kieran O'Doherty, Martin Berger, Ernest Partridge, December 6, 1964; nebel_0080-0083; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 5)
    - Roger Caras, Miles Kreuger, Samuel Vandervirt, Carl Kauffeld, Ernest Partridge, December 13, 1964; nebel_0084-0089; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 5)
    - Rev. David Poling, Rabbi Aaron Pearl, Rev. Robert Schrock, Stewart Robb, Knigh Deigh, December 17, 1964; nebel_0090-0092; 3 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 5)
    - John Steinway, Miles Kreuger, Roy Schatt, Stewart Robb, December 23, 1964; nebel_0093-0097; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 5, 6)
    - (aired 1967 June 15) Kenneth Knigin, Rev. Robert Schrock, Rabbi Samuel Silver, Roy Schatt, Stewart Robb, December 27, 1964; nebel_0098-0099; 2 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 6)
    - "Ethics-Law" Herman Glaser, Kieran O'Doherty, Rev. Robert Schrock, Kenneth Knigin, January 17, 1965; nebel_0100-0105; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 6)
    - "Radio" William Randall, Miles Kreuger, Norman Raslin, Benjamin Hall, January 20, 1965; nebel_0106-0110; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 6)
    - (repeated 1965 May 24) Henry Morgan, Dee Anthony, Edward Spingarn, Lester Del Rey, January 22, 1965; nebel_0111-0115; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 6, 7)
    - Harry Treu, January 25, 1965; nebel_0116; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 7)
    - Jack Carter, Eli Basse, Morton Gunty, Robert Sydney, Daniel Crystal, Jack London (not the author), January 27, 1965; nebel_0117-0121; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 7)
    - "Capital Punishment" Chaplain Robert Weeks, Richard Plechner, Kieran O'Doherty, Sanford Teller, January 28, 1965; nebel_0122-0126; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 7)
    - "Five Figure Income" James Sheeran, Kenneth Knigin, Al Lottman, Sanford Teller, Michael Klepper, February 3, 1965; nebel_0127-0131; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 7)
    - "New York City In Crisis" (aired 1966 March 22) Barry Gottehrer, Kieran O'Doherty, Al Lottman, Sanford Teller, February 6, 1965; nebel_0132-0134; 3 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 7)
    - (repeated 1967 April 9) Sherry Britten (exotic dancer) Jacqueline Susann, Al Lottman, Dee Anthony, February 14, 1965; nebel_0135-0140; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 7, 8)
    - Dayton Allen, Dee Anthony, Will Ousler, James Donnelly, February 18, 1965; nebel_0141-0145; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 8)
    - "Medical Jurisprudence" Dr. George Freidman, Dr. Howard Miller, Joseph Lampl, Bernard Chorosh, February 19, 1965; nebel_0146-0150; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 8)
    - "Iwo Jima" Richard Newcomb, Kieran O'Doherty, Sanford Teller, Roy Schatt, February 21, 1965; nebel_0151-0155; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 8)
    - "Positive Action" (aired 1965 March 13, repeated 1965 August 20) Gyula Beaves, March 9, 1965; nebel_0156; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 8)
    - "Minimum Wage Law" David Livingston, Martin Berger, Robert Becker, Donald Spanier, March 13, 1965; nebel_0157-0161; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 9)
    - "Laser Beam" David Andrews, Frederik Pohl, Kenneth Knigin, Roy Schatt, March 14, 1965; nebel_0162-0167; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 9)
    - "Women's House of Detention" Herman Glaser, Joseph Kottler, Kenneth Knigin, John Morrin, Beth Cosnow, March 27, 1965; nebel_0168-0172; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 9)
    - (repeated 1965 August 17) Phil Foster, Arthur Kopit, Lew Parker, Edward Spingarn, March 31, 1965; nebel_0173-0177; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 9, 10)
    - (aired 1966 September 16) Lew Parker, Shirley Herr, Jacqueline Susann, Morton Gunty, April 4, 1965; nebel_0178; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 10)
    - "Psychological Testing" Dr. Edward McAllister, Kenneth Knigin, Lee Steiner, Roy Schatt, April 23, 1965; nebel_0179-0182; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 10)
    - "Defender Dogs" Preston Golden, Edith Aynes, Roy Schatt, Kenneth Knigin, May 13, 1965; nebel_0183-0187; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 10)
    - Emile Seerup, May 17, 1965; nebel_0188; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 10)
    - "Red Spies In The U.N." (repeated 1966 February 12, 1966 March 25) Pierre Huss, Robert Jorio, Roy Schatt, Frederik Pohl, May 20, 1965; nebel_0189-0193; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 10)
    - (repeated 1965 September 12) Ralph Ginzburg, Al Lottman, Kenneth Knigin, Will Ouster, May 23, 1965; nebel_0194-0199; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 10, 11)
    - Leonard Levine, May 24, 1965; nebel_0200; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 11)
    - William Filler, June 15, 1965; nebel_0201; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 11)
    - (repeated 1965 July 18) Phil Foster, Robert Orben, Jerry Shane, Edward Spingarn, June 16, 1965; nebel_0202-0206; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 11)
    - George Kyotow, Rudy Maschke, Samuel Vandervirt, Sanford Teller, June 25, 1965; nebel_0207-0211; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 11)
    - (aired 1966 December 18) Gordon Hall, Charles Rice, Brad Crandall, David McReynolds, Al Lottman, June 26, 1965; nebel_0212-0214; 3 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 11)
    - (repeated 1966 March 1) Thomas Wolfe, Charles Ruddock, Sanford Teller, Michael Girsdansky, June 27, 1965; nebel_0215-0220; 6 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 11, 12)
    - Morton Herman, June 30, 1965; nebel_0221; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 12)
    - Al Salzman, July 6, 1965; nebel_0222; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 12)
    - "The Rabbi" (repeated 1966 March 8) Noah Gordon, Dr. Lee Steiner, Rev. Robert Schrock, Charles Raddock, July 8, 1965; nebel_0223-0227; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 12)
    - "Jackpot" Al Lottman, Kenneth Knigin, Dr. Robert Rowan, Charles Raddock, July 11, 1965; nebel_0228-0232; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 12)
    - "Backache" Dr. Hans Kraus, July 20, 1965; nebel_0233; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 12)
    - Morton Gunty, July 22, 1965; nebel_0234-0235; 2 reels (1/4"x1200'), 7" (Oversize 12)
    - Ward Cannel, Al Lottman, Charles Raddock, Sanford Teller, July 23, 1965; nebel_0236-0240; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 12, 13)
    - (repeated 1965 December 26) Ian Ballantine, Book Publisher Lester Del Rey, Charles Raddock, Will Ousler, July 28, 1965; nebel_0241-0245; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 13)
    - (aired 1965 December 17) Al Lottman, Dr. S. K. Fineberg, Dr. Howard Miller, Eden Grey, August 11, 1965; nebel_0246-0247; 2 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 13)
    - "Street Singer" Arthur Tracy (author) Dee Anthony, Miles Kreuger, Charles Raddock, August 13, 1965; nebel_0248-0252; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 13)
    - "War of the Flea" (aired 1967 August 6) Robert Taber, Martin Berger, Al Lottman, Robert Jorio, August 21, 1965; nebel_0253-0254; 2 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 13)
    - "Rosenberg And Sobel Case" (repeated 1965 September 20) Walter Schneir (author) Roy Cohn, Kenneth Knigin, Frederik Pohl, August 22, 1965; nebel_0255-0259; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 13, 14)
    - "111 Days In Stanleyville" David Reed, Kieran O'Doherty, Michael Girsdansky, Sanford Teller, August 25, 1965; nebel_0260-0264; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 14)
    - "Autographs" (repeated 1965 December 14) Charles Hamilton, S. K. Fineberg, Rev. Robert Schrock, Roy Schatt, August 27, 1965; nebel_0265-0269; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 14)
    - "Education Of A Broadcaster" (repeated 1965 November 23) Harry Bannister, Al Lottman, Roy Schatt, September 1, 1965; nebel_0270-0274; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 14)
    - Lena Basquette, S. K. Fineberg, Sanford Teller, Miles Kreuger, September 8, 1965; nebel_0275-0279; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 14, 15)
    - "The Liberal Establishment" M. Stanton Evans, Martin Berger, Kieran O'Doherty, Sanford Teller, September 16, 1965; nebel_0280-0284; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 15)
    - Frank Farrell, James Shanahan, Patricia Marano, Douglas Kingman, October 8, 1965; nebel_0286-0289; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 15)
    - Mr. Roff Jr., October 20, 1965; nebel_0290; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 15)
    - "Magician's Magic" Paul Curry, Bruce Elliot, Sanford Teller, Jack London, Jerry Shane, October 21, 1965; nebel_0291-0294; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 15)
    - "Food Facts And Fallacies" (repeated 1965 December 7) Herbert Bailey, Dr. Howard Miller, S. K. Fineberg, Samuel Vandervirt, October 22, 1965; nebel_0295-0299; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 15, 16)
    - (repeated 1965 November 30) Erika Freeman, Jacqueline Susann, Al Lottman, Charles Raddock, Paris Flammonde, Michael Girsdansky, Stewart Robb, October 24, 1965; nebel_0300-0304; unknown, 10-1/2" (Oversize 16)
    - "Black Friday" (repeated 1965 December 21) Joel Fisch, Al Lottman, Roy Schatt, October 29, 1965; nebel_0305-0309; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 16)
    - "India" Dr. Marendra Sethi, Allen MacKenzie, Roy Schatt, Howard Miller, Sanford Teller, October 30, 1965; nebel_0310-0313; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 16)
    - Dr. Albert Burke, Sanford Teller, Kenneth Knigin, October 30, 1965; nebel_0314; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 16)
    - (repeated 1967 January 24) Roy Cohn, Charles Markman, Kenneth Knigin, November 13, 1965; nebel_0315-0318; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 16)
    - Benjamin Freedman, Rabbi Aaron Pearl, November 15, 1965; nebel_0319-0322; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 17)
    - "Cyborg" Lester Del Rey, Robert Rowan, Michael Girsdansky, November 19, 1965; nebel_0323; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 17)
    - Roy Schatt, Jack London, November 26, 1965; nebel_0324-0326; 3 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 17)
    - "Nation On Wheels" Frank Donovan, Samuel Vandervirt, Shirley Herz, Leslie Dorsey, December 2, 1965; nebel_0327-0330; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 17)
    - "Computers" (repeated 1966 February 2) Henry W. Simon, Arthur Elias, Eugene Leonard, Frederik Pohl, December 4, 1965; nebel_0331-0334; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 17)
    - "Sukarno" (repeated 1966 April 19) Cindy Abams, Sanford Teller, Will Ousler, Lyle Stuart, Frederik Pohl, December 11, 1965; nebel_0335-0338; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 17)
    - "Conservatism" (repeated 1966 January 25) Kent Courtney, Kieran O'Doherty, Al Lottman, December 15, 1965; nebel_0339-0342; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 18)
    - Lyle Stuart, Kenneth Knigin, Lawrence Schwartz, December 15, 1965; nebel_0343; 1 reel, 10-1/2" (Oversize 18)
    - "Advertising" Charles Adams, Sanford Teller, Roy Schatt, Anthony Capiello, December 16, 1965; nebel_0344-0347; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 18)
    - "Our Depleted Society" (aired 1966 July 6) Seymour Heiman, Lester Del Rey, Samuel Vandervirt, December 17, 1965; nebel_0348-0349; 2 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 18)
    - "Mental Health And The Schools" James Mahorter, Edward Spingarn, Kenneth Knigin, Ernest Partridge, December 24, 1965; nebel_0352-0356; 5 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 18)
    - Richard Copland, Jack Ryan, Kenneth Knigin, Robert Schrock, January 6, 1966; nebel_0357-0359; 3 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 19)
    - "Revolt Of The Damned" Daniel Kurzman, Sanford Teller, Will Ousler, Frederik Pohl, Robert Cochnar, January 9, 1966; nebel_0360-0363; 4 reels, 10-1/2" (Oversize 19)
    - "Future Photography" Harry Gosho, Sanford Teller, William Clark, Anthony Cappiello, January 14, 1966; nebel_0365-0369; 5 reels (Oversize 19)
    - "Dynamic Mental Laws For Successful Living" Anthony Norvell, Lee Steiner, Rev. Robert Schrock, Dr. S. K. Fineberg, January 16, 1966; nebel_0370-0373; 4 reels (Oversize 19)
    - "ESP" Alan J. Lerner, Jess Stern (author) Dr. Berthold Swartz, January 19, 1966; nebel_0374-0377; 4 reels (Oversize 19)
    - Dee Anthony, Pat Henry, January 19, 1966; nebel_0378; 1 reel (Oversize 19)
    - "Obscenity Litigation" O. John Rogge, Ralph Ginsburg, Kenneth Knigin, January 22, 1966; nebel_0379-0382; 4 reels (Oversize 20)
    - P. J. Sidney, Malcolm X, January 28, 1966; nebel_0383-0387; 5 reels (Oversize 20)
    - "The Anatomy Of A Success" Nicholas Darvas, Lee Steiner, Al Lottman, February 19, 1966; nebel_0388-0392; 5 reels (Oversize 20)
    - "John Birch Society" John Rousselot, Thomas Davis, Will Ousler, Kieran O'Doherty, March 30, 1966; nebel_0399-0403; 5 reels (Oversize 21)
    - Robert Goldman, Dr. S. K. Fineberg, Roy Schatt, Sanford Teller, April 1, 1966; nebel_0404; 1 reel (Oversize 21)